NGUYEN VIET HUNG

Phone: (+84) 913 977511 Email: ng.hung83@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Full-stack developer with more than 10 years of experience in IT industry. Strong experience in software development, using a wide range of programming languages, especially in Java, others include Ruby, Go, Python, JavaScript, etc. Have robust background of OOP and design patterns. Familiar with many OSes, including OSX, Unix-*, and Windows.

Effective in problem solving, and excel at debugging. Willing to learn and always try to catch up with new technologies. Have positive work ethic and good work history. Strive for perfection in quality.

EDUCATION

2001 – 2005 HCMC University of Technology Computer Science, Talented Engineer Course

Tien Giang

HCMC

GitHub: @tvhung83

1998 – 2001 Tien Giang High school for The Gifted Education Informatics

AWARD

2001 High school National Contest Consolation Prize, Programming

Vietnam

1999 Olympic 4/30 Bronze medal, Programming

Da Nang

WORK EXPERIENCE

11/2016 - Now Treasure Data Inc. Senior Software Engineer

Mountain View, CA

- Implement Data Connector to import/export from/to 3rd party services, such as Facebook Ads, Microsoft PowerBI, Zendesk, etc.
 - O Write Embulk plugins in Java and Ruby.
 - O Unit tests with Circle CI and Travis CI.
- Implement customized OAuth/OAuth2 strategies in Ruby (used in API platform).
- Write integrate/system tests in Ruby.
- Release new updates to production.
- Monitor data connectors and take action if needed.

- Write high level design documents (for each Data Connector).
- Collaborate with 3rd party services' staffs to resolve issues and overcome limitations.

12/2015 – 06/2016 Zen Marketing (full-time since 02/2016) HCMC Senior Software Engineer

- Collect and aggregate advertising data of mobile applications, and from multiple ad networks. Clients are most popular mobile app companies, such as Zynga, Lyft, etc.
- Build data importers, which includes some main categories as below:
 - o Web scraper with Selenium web driver.
 - o API consuming with Apache HttpClient.
 - o Email importing by Java daemon.
- Maintain and update importers as needed, when website or API is changed.
- Research and implement a tool to detect/group ad images based on similarity percentage.
- Occasionally collaborate with ad network's staffs to investigate and resolve data issues.

12/2014 – 02/2016 Harvey Nash Vietnam HCMC Senior Software Engineer

- UnifiedSocial: develop back-end APIs using Golang.
- Build front-end application using various modern JS frameworks, such as EmberJS, Ember Data, Bootstrap, etc. along with its technologies, NodeJS and Bower.
- Develop back-end APIs using Jersey, a JAX-RS implementation which is included in Glassfish server, and use Jackson library to expose API under JSON format.
- Build web application with PrimesFaces 5.1, an extension of JSF2.
- Deploy app to Glassfish 4.1 server.
- Use MySQL database, involve writing stored procedures.
- Revision control by git.

12/2013 – 11/2014 Simple Solutions Taipan VN HCMC Technical Lead

- Take part in developing the VMS (Volunteer Management System) for SEAGames 2015 in Singapore:
 - o Public website using Liferay.
 - o SSO using CAS (Central Authentication Service).
 - Back-end application for volunteer profile management, broadcasting messages via multiple channels, e-learning, etc. Technologies used: Spring Boot, Spring Security, JPA via Hibernate, MySQL.
- Manage a small team of 3-5 members.

- Discuss with onshore technical manager on a daily basis, to plan and design the implementation.
- Work with BA team to clarify requirements.

01/2013 – 11/2013 Cosatech Co., Ltd

HCMC

Team Leader

- Work for CBOE (Chicago Board Options Exchange), the largest U.S options exchange and creator of listed options, particularly in building various shell scripts to surveil options trading. Technologies used: ksh scripting, PL/SQL on Oracle 11.
- Enhance WBS (Web-based Surveillance) tool. Technologies used: EJB, Struts 1.x, Oracle 11, Jetty.
- Manage a small team of 5 members.
- Work with onshore PM on a daily basis.
- Plans and tasks management.
- Technical documenting.

10/2008 – 12/2012 i-POP Networds Pte Ltd Senior Software Engineer

HCMC

- Build mobile webs for world-class brands in Southeast Asia area, such as mobile ESPN, Bloomberg, Cartoon Network, Electronic Arts.
- Sport feeds parsing daemon.
- Build services to process and broadcast SMS.
- Technologies used: Spring Core, Spring MVC, Hibernate ORM, XML processing, Hessian (web service), MySQL, HTML/CSS (especially for mobile handsets).

12/2007 - 09/2008 ASAO Corp., Ltd Team Leader / Senior Developer

HCMC

- Marketing websites for online games to release in Cambodia: JX2, RF, etc.
- Marketing websites for mobile value added services.
- Build services to communicate with SMS gateway: process incoming and send outgoing messages.
- Manage a small team of 2 members.
- Technologies used: ZendFramework, MySQL, HTML/CSS/JS.

06/2006 – 11/2007 Mobile Solution Services., Ltd Team Leader / Senior Developer

HCMC

- Build marketing websites for SMS value added services: SMS bidding games, mobile content downloading, etc.
- Handy Community: first community of user-generated contents for mobile in Vietnam.
- Develop SMS-related web services.
- Manage web team of 5 members.

 Technologies used: ZendFramework, MySQL, HTML/CSS/JS, ffmpeg for converting video formats on real-time.

REFERENCES

Yao Lu

Engineer Manager at Treasure Data Inc.

Ian Morrison

Founder of GKxIM Vietnam.

Phan Cong Thanh

Former Founder of Mobile Solution Services, former Head of Atlassian Vietnam, and CEO of EgoPulse.

HOBBY

Hacking

- Hackintosh: Don't you love Mac OS X? Isn't it the OS of perfection? If you buy a Mac, you'd miss all the funs. As a Mac enthusiast, I enjoy making it run on a PC.
- Interested in reversing web resource protection, such as figure out commercial websites' APIs and use them in personal projects.
- Always seek new usage and add new functionalities to embedded devices, make them useful as much as possible.

Linux

 Passionate in Linux, especially embedded systems. I love exploring and hacking a variety of embedded devices running Linux, from Raspberry Pi, NAS to WiFi routers.

Entertainment

• A cinephile and an audiophile.